(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
♪ (TENSE MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
(DOOR RATTLES, CREAKS OPEN)
♪ (MUSIC BUILDS) ♪
- (GRUNTS)
- ♪ (MUSIC STOPS) ♪
What the fuck?
It's time to get up, Junior.
JOHN STEWART JUNIOR:
What did the Guardians say?
About what?
We got four dead aliens
on a football field.
Another one just blew up
half the sheriff's station.
Oh yeah,
I'm not calling the Guardians.
JOHN: Then what the fuck
are you doing here, Hal?
- I'm training you.
- (BUCKET CLANGS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
(DOOR RATTLES)
No, no, really.
You just take your time.
What the fuck
are we doing, Jordan?
What're you talking about?
You've been busting my balls
for a month to learn how to fly.
- Today's the day
you're gonna learn.
- We got a case to work.
Jesus Christ Almighty.
Unclench.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
You ready?
(DISTANT TRAIN HORN BLARING)
You fly.
Fly?
- Fly.
- (CHUCKLES)
(SCOFFS) That's it?
Just... just fly?
Oh, no, no, no, no.
I-- I-- I'm sorry.
- Fly, please.
- Ah.
HAL JORDAN: Look,
it's supposed to be instinctual.
Just concentrate.
- Me, I'm a fighter pilot.
- JOHN: So I've heard.
When I think "fly,"
it's automatic.
See-- Just concentrate.
- Think flight.
- JOHN: Mm-hmm.
Great. Thank you.
Back up a little bit.
♪ (LOW BROODING MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
(GRUNTS SOFTLY)
(INHALES DEEPLY)
(GRUNTS)
(RING WARBLING SOFTLY)
(BIRD CHIRPING)
(WINGS FLAPPING)
What the fuck is that?
Uh, I think that's a bird, sir.
Uh...
Why don't you drop
the "sir" bullshit.
- We both know you don't mean it.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Whatever you say.
(CHIRPING)
♪ (MUSIC FADING) ♪
- (RING PULSING)
- AUTOMATED VOICE:
Ring nearing depletion.
- All right, new lesson.
Gratis. Gimme the ring.
- (RING HUMS WEAKLY)
- Come on.
- (CHIRPING)
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
♪ (POIGNANT MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
Is there a problem?
- No. No.
- ♪ (BROODING STRING
MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
Ring gets low on charge,
there's a...
(BIRD CHIRPING)
...one-time trick re-up.
You just gotta...
(CHIRPING)
Just gotta hit it flush.
- (RING HUMS SHARPLY)
- AUTOMATED VOICE:
Ring charge, five percent.
- All right.
- ♪ (MUSIC CONCLUDES) ♪
New flight plan.
- I booked you a window.
- I don't understand.
HAL: On an airplane.
There's seats near the windows,
there's seats near the aisles,
and there's seats
in the middle too.
Nobody wants those, uh--
Look, the point is I need
the lantern to charge the ring.
I need you
to go back to Coast City
to my place and get it.
The, uh, address is on the back
and the...
the key is out front
under the rock.
But, Hal,
this is already booked.
- (BIRD CHIRPING)
- (WINGS FLAPPING)
Wait, so what would you
have done if I could fly?
Well, you didn't fly, did you?
So, it doesn't really matter.
Now get yourself ready.
I need that lantern.
Oh, uh...
One more thing.
Uh, feed Earl for me, would you?
- His food's in the icebox.
- And what's Earl?
- Is it a dog? Cat?
- (CHIRPING)
HAL: You know what?
And one more training exercise.
Take that... that bird with you
and bring it back alive.
You lose concentration,
it disappears.
It disappears, you fail.
Don't fail.
(CHIRPING)
And what are you gonna be doing?
HAL: Enjoying
not answering your questions.
(DOOR CLOSES)
♪ (BROODING GUITAR
RIFF PLAYING) ♪
♪ (MUSIC FADES) ♪
♪ (PENSIVE MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
♪ (BROODING MUSIC OVERLAPPING) ♪
(SPRINKLERS HISSING)
♪ (INTRIGUING MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
(CROWBAR THUDS)
(GRILLE CLATTERS)
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
AUTOMATED VOICE:
You've reached the Rushville
Sheriff's Department.
If this is an emergency,
please hang up and dial 911.
Otherwise,
please leave a message
and someone
from the department...
♪ (INTRIGUING MUSIC CONTINUES) ♪
(KEYS JINGLING)
♪ (MUSIC FADES) ♪
(RING WARBLES)
♪ (LOW BROODING MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
HAL: There you are.
- (RING PULSING)
- AUTOMATED VOICE: This ring
will soon run out of charge.
- Fuck.
- AUTOMATED VOICE: Three,
two, one.
- (EXHALES SHARPLY)
- (CAR DOOR CLOSES)
- (CAR ENGINE REVVING)
- (TIRES SCREECHING)
♪ (BROODING MUSIC CONTINUES) ♪
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(KERRY KANE SPEAKING
INDISTINCTLY ON MICROPHONE)
- (CITIZEN SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
- (OVERLAPPING CHATTER)
(CHATTER STOPS)
- (DOOR HINGES CREAKING)
- ♪ (MUSIC FADES) ♪
Were you talking about me?
- (CHAIRS CREAKING)
- (FAINT MURMURS)
You were talking about me.
(SOFTLY) Excuse me.
Excuse me.
(CLEARS THROAT)
(FAINT MURMURS CONTINUE)
Carry on.
We were just talking
about whether to go ahead
with this Friday's
football game.
Would that be traumatizing,
or could it help
pull the community together?
Coach,
you were about to say something.
Right. Yeah. Um...
I've been talking to the boys,
and, uh,
they're pretty shook up.
- This is also something
they've been working for...
- (QUIETLY) Hey.
- since two-a-days.
- (WHISPERS INDISTINCTLY)
COACH: Uh, I mean... (SIGHS)
- I guess I wonder what we're...
- BILL MACON: (WHISPERS)
Sorry. Sorry.
...what we're teaching 'em
if we just pack it up
and forfeit.
- KERRY: Yeah, I think that's
what we're trying to figure out.
- (QUIETLY) Good news.
- I got the judge
to drop your assault charges.
- (COACH RESUMES SPEAKING)
- Well, I appreciate that.
- (CHUCKLES)
- How much is it gonna cost me?
- Oh, no. It's on the house.
KERRY:
And, obviously, we're worried...
Good news is you're free
to go back to Coast City.
Or anywhere else you feel like
going for that matter.
What was everyone talking about
when I came in here?
KERRY: ...well-placed,
to go ahead with the game
and playing.
Five people just died here.
An alien blew himself up
at the sheriff's station.
That's a lot to process.
Did your wife tell you
that alien was chirping
about vengeance
before he blew himself up?
Here's what I'd really like
to talk to you about.
I ended up
on that football field
because of a hunch. Hmm.
Just a gut feeling
that it was
gonna be extraterrestrial.
But your father's men,
they shot four people.
And yet, those guys' friend
ends up being an alien?
(COACH SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
Is that a... a question or...
Uh, it's just a roundabout way
of saying
you don't shoot people
because of a gut feeling.
- I... I wouldn't know--
- HAL: No, I'm telling you.
- You don't.
- Okay.
So, how is it that father's men
knew who to target?
You'd have to ask him,
I don't--
HAL: I'm asking you
as my attorney,
someone who cares
about my wellbeing,
and apparently,
my travel schedule.
We are still talking
with attorney-client privilege,
I presume.
KERRY: Excuse me, honey?
BOTH: Yes?
KERRY: I was talking
to my husband.
Oh. Oh, yeah. Of course.
If you two
are gonna keep talking,
I'm gonna need
Mr. Jordan to leave.
- He started it.
- Well...
I've got about 30 seconds
of patience left.
I only need 40.
KERRY: And I'll be happy
to give them to you
when we're done here.
Well, how long
is that gonna take?
- (MICROPHONE SCREECHING)
- It'll take as long as it takes.
Yeah, I don't think
I can keep quiet that long.
- (CELL PHONE RINGING)
- (FAINT CHATTER)
Oh, uh, sorry,
I gotta... I gotta take this.
Yeah. As you were.
Talk to me, Junior.
- JOHN: This house is insane.
- (BIRD CHIRPING)
HAL: That's what you called
to tell me?
JOHN: No, no,
I can't find the key.
HAL: Well, did you look
under the rock?
Which rock, Hal?
HAL: To the left
of the door under the bush.
(GRUNTS)
- It looks like a potato
with a smile.
- (CAR ENGINE STARTING)
HAL: Or a frown
if I left it upside down.
Potato rock.
♪ (SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
(KEY CLATTERS)
(CHIRPS)
So, how's it going over there?
I get the feeling
everyone wants me gone.
Kinda makes me feel
like I need to stick around.
It would make you think that.
HAL: The lantern's in my closet.
If you're at the front door,
it's upstairs to the left.
So, how much
do Lanterns get paid anyway?
Not enough.
I can tell you that.
- JOHN: Well,
your house begs to differ.
- (DOOR RATTLING)
(GLASS CLATTERING)
- JOHN: What the hell was that?
- Don't worry about it.
I got the house from a rich guy.
Saved his kid.
His dad felt like shit
because he couldn't help.
I didn't want to emasculate him
anymore, so I...
let him buy me a house.
So, when are you actually going
to move into this place?
What are you talking about?
I've lived in that house
for eight years.
- JOHN: You've got no furniture.
- (GRUNTS) I have a bed.
I found your room.
HAL: The lantern's in a box
in the back of the closet.
Go into the hallway
and turn right.
(PANTING)
♪ (RIVETING INSTRUMENTAL
MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
JOHN: Hey, do you, um...
need me to bring
a uniform back or something?
Not unless you're gonna teach me
how someone takes a piss
in one of those goddamn things.
♪ (MUSIC BUILDS) ♪
(GRUNTS)
- JOHN: I see the box.
- (DOORS CLOSE)
HAL: (PANTING) Good.
It's voice-activated,
so when you get it next to you,
put me on speaker.
(GRUNTS)
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Greetings, Hal Jordan.
To access the vault,
please confirm identity.
Ready.
Mogo doesn't socialize.
(MECHANICAL WHIRRING)
HAL: Open the box.
The lantern's in there.
♪ (UNSETTLING MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
It's pitch-black.
(STRAINING)
It's a pocket dimension, Junior.
Just... just feel around
in there and...
(GRUNTS) ...you'll find it.
(BIRD CHIRPS)
♪ (UNSETTLING MUSIC CONTINUES) ♪
(DIMENSION BOX HUMMING)
(BIRD CHIRPING DISTANTLY)
(METALLIC CLANG)
I got it.
Don't forget to feed Earl.
Spoons are on the counter.
(PANTS)
♪ (RIVETING INSTRUMENTAL
MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
♪ (MUSIC FADES) ♪
(PANTS)
(BIRD CHIRPS)
♪ (SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
JOHN: Earl?
Hey, Earl.
Dinner time.
(HAL GRUNTS)
JOHN: Earl?
Got your favorite.
Uh, beef and bison.
Earl?
(CHIRPING)
Hey, Earl, listen, I, uh...
I don't know where you are,
but, um, kinda ready
to be done with this meat.
♪ (MUSIC RISES) ♪
- (EARL GROWLS)
- (SOFTLY) Jeez!
- (BIRD SCREECHING)
- ♪ (MUSIC CONCLUDES) ♪
(HISSES, GROWLS)
What the hell is wrong
with you, Jordan?
(EARL GROWLING)
What's up, man?
Hey, Earl. I'm, uh...
I'm John, and I'm...
I'm here to feed you.
- Just don't eat my bird.
- (EARL GROWLS)
All right.
- There you...
- (CHOMPS)
JOHN: You know,
uh, once upon a time,
hamburgers used
to be my thing, too.
- (ROARS)
- Whoa! Hey!
(BELLOWS, MUNCHES)
(CHUCKLES)
Fucking Jordan.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(HAL GRUNTS)
(FEET THUDDING)
(GRUNTING)
(DETECTOR CHIRPS)
- (PANTING)
- (SCANNER CHIRPS)
♪ (LOW TENSE MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
(GROANS)
(BIRD CHIRPING)
(JOHN GASPS, GROANS)
♪ (INTENSE MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
(GROANS)
(TASER CRACKLING)
- (RUMBLING)
- ♪ (MUSIC FADES) ♪
(JOHN GRUNTS)
(PANTS)
Where are we going?
Where's my fucking bird?
Your bird's safe.
(CHIRPS)
- (ASSAILANT YELPS)
- ♪ (INTENSE MUSIC RESUMES) ♪
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(ASSAILANT GROANS)
♪ (MUSIC RISES) ♪
- (GRUNTS)
- (ASSAILANT GROANS)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(GROANS)
(JOHN GROANING)
(BIRD CHIRPING)
(BOTH YELL)
- (CAR HORNS HONKING)
- (TIRES SCREECHING)
♪ (INTENSE MUSIC CONTINUES) ♪
(CAR HORN BLARING)
(CAR HORNS BLARING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
♪ (MUSIC BUILDS) ♪
(CHIRPING)
(DRIVER YELPS)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
- (ECHOING THUD)
- ♪ (MUSIC CONCLUDES) ♪
(POLICE SIREN WAILING)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(CAR ENGINE RUNNING)
Is this about me
not being on the insurance?
(SNIFFS)
It is pretty much
exactly what it looks like.
But in my defense,
I wanted to talk to you
about this at the meeting,
and you shushed me.
You're killing me, Jordan.
You know that?
Just a slow, painful death.
There's more going on here
than you realize.
You mean like you going
to the stadium
and dragging these corpses
through the metal detector,
which you now realize
is actually an alien detector?
Uh, let me rephrase.
You obviously realize
exactly what's going on here.
Congratulations.
You've caught up to me.
Now, would you just please
let me do my job?
Is this a good time
to talk about jurisdiction?
Because you seemed
really hung up
on what was terrestrial
and what wasn't.
- And as far as--
- Where are you going
with these guys?
To visit your father-in-law.
May I just say,
that is a profoundly bad idea.
Did he put up those detectors?
- He did.
- Do you know where he got them?
- I do not.
- You're not even curious?
It's not against the law
to be obsessed with aliens.
Trust me, I wish it was.
It'd make my marriage
a hell of a lot smoother.
Your marriage is unsmooth?
The fact is, Macon hasn't done
anything illegal.
Now, he was cordial
when he needed you,
but if you show up today
with all your questions
and all your attitude,
it is not gonna go well.
Whose side are you on?
- ♪ (BROODING MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
- (SNIFFS, EXHALES SHARPLY)
I'll take you,
but you let me do the talking.
Understood?
- Well, I don't know if I--
- Just nod.
KERRY: Follow me.
♪ (BROODING MUSIC CONTINUES) ♪
Hey, Ben.
I'd like to see
your boss, please.
I'm afraid
he's not accepting visitors.
Yeah, I get that. Absolutely.
You know, sometimes
you just gotta accept things
that take you
out of your comfort zone.
Is he speaking for you?
Right now,
he's pretty much just speaking.
This is part of
an official investigation, son.
- Is that true?
- Evidently.
Well, in that case,
can I see your warrant?
Well, look at that. The cavalry.
Just in the nick of time.
(HORSE NEIGHS)
The calvary's a lot faster
in the movies.
I told them
you aren't seeing any visitors.
That's okay, Ben. Hey, Kerry.
You know I'm a fan of your work.
But I confess, I'm confused
as to why you're still in town.
Four aliens are dead.
Their accomplice
blew himself up.
And yet, you linger.
Well, that's what
your son told me.
But, uh...
Well, here's what I think.
I think you're hiding something
on this property
you don't want me to see.
I had you as a guest here
just the other day.
Because you wanted me to prove
that that fella
in custody was an alien.
Which you did. Like I said,
I'm a fan of your work,
- but your work here's done.
- Oh, I just need a minute
- of your time.
- I believe you've had it.
♪ (LOW TENSE MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
Front gate, eleven o'clock.
(RADIO BEEPING)
Oh, boy.
Am I about to be threatened?
I got four dead bodies in my car
that set off
the hidden camera and alarm
when I drag 'em
through those metal detectors
you got set up
at the stadium there.
Now, I don't want to disparage
your small, little town,
but I've been
all over the galaxy,
and I don't think
I've ever seen technology
quite that sophisticated.
I told you.
People who walked this land
before me,
they got caught flat-footed
when the settlers come in
and colonized 'em.
I'm not about to make
that same mistake again.
And how about that technology?
Very generous gift from the man
who funds this property.
- Oh, your benefactor?
- WILL MACON: Correct.
Tell me the truth.
Is he even real,
or is this some
Keyser Söze situation?
Oh, I assure you,
he's very real.
HAL:
Then what's his name again?
I'm not at liberty to say.
- Because of the NDA.
- WILL: That's right.
That's-- You know,
- do all cowboys have NDAs...
- That's it.
- We're leaving.
- ...or are you just
a special cowboy?
No, I'm serious.
You got this whole Marlboro Man
thing happening here,
but yet you can't be straight
with me because of an NDA?
Hell, even that other guy,
he was selling cigarettes
to kids,
and he still didn't let
those lawyers stop him
from saying
whatever the hell he wanted.
I want to know
what other technology you got
in this compound.
I think
it's important for you to know
there's a man with a rifle
in that guard tower
with instructions
to shoot anybody
who trespasses on this property.
♪ (MUSIC BUILDS) ♪
Well, you can't do that.
- Can he do that?
- He can absolutely do that.
Well, that just seems
unneighborly.
Sheriff.
HAL: I'm coming on.
You're gonna have to deal
with me.
Oh, for Christ's sake,
I got the ring.
You try to shoot me,
and I'm just gonna put up--
♪ (MUSIC STOPS ABRUPTLY) ♪
- (CHAIR RATTLING)
- (JOHN BREATHING HEAVILY)
I apologize for the violence.
- (BIRD CHIRPING)
- Yeah.
May I ask you a question
about the bird, John Stewart?
Sure.
It's a wildly
impressive construct,
but how does
Hal Jordan continue
to project it
from such a great distance?
He's not projecting it. I am.
You're not wearing a ring.
Did you tie me up
to ask me questions
about my fucking bird?
No, I tied you up
to ask you about Manhunters.
I'm sorry.
Was I supposed to react?
Yeah, you are.
Because you think
I know what a Manhunter is?
ANTAAN: Given your proximity
to Hal Jordan,
it'd be very hard
to believe that you do not.
Proximity. You mean "closeness"?
That's a better word, yes.
That's a much better word.
JOHN: I see human
isn't your first language here.
I'm not even close
to close with Hal Jordan.
In fact, he sent me here
to get rid of me,
so I'm sorry, gentlemen.
♪ (FOREBODING MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
But you're about to torture
a man
who doesn't know shit.
(LAUGHS)
Torture? No, John.
We don't want
to torture you, John.
We want to recruit you.
You don't tell someone
when you wanna recruit them.
You have to be more subtle.
ANTAAN: We don't have time
for subtlety, John.
One of the most dangerous beings
to ever exist
knows it has been found,
which means right now
it is preparing
its brutal response.
And that's a Manhunter?
You think the Green Lanterns
came first?
- You really don't know?
- I really don't know.
Well, that makes things
much easier.
I don't have to change
your mind.
I just need to stamp it.
What the fuck
do you mean, stamp?
Imprint? Um...
- Enlighten.
- I don't need enlightenment.
There was a time of chaos
in the galaxy.
- Then the Manhunters came.
- (MECHANISM CLICKING)
ANTAAN: We don't know
where they came from,
just that they were synthetic.
And able to build new bodies,
which meant they could take
the form of any species
and embed, undetected,
within any society.
This ability to build
allowed them
to invent technologies
far beyond the limits
of the planets they inhabited.
They were brutal.
They were deceptive.
They carried out
what they called "justice."
Entire species were lost.
(DEVICE CLICKS, HUMS)
ANTAAN: And then,
as mysteriously as they arrived,
they were gone.
At least
we thought they were gone.
In reality, one of them remained
on our planet,
passing as one of us
while he quietly engineered
a holocaust.
Have you ever been deceived
by someone you love?
Yeah.
Then you'll understand
when you experience
what he did to us.
♪ (MUSIC BUILDS) ♪
(CHIRPING)
Get off. (GRUNTS)
I'm sorry, but you need to see.
- (DEVICE BUZZING)
- (GROANS)
- ♪ (OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
- (SCREAMS)
ANTAAN: This is what
it looks like
when a Manhunter
destroys your people.
John, do you see
what it feels like?
(JOHN SOBS)
- ANTAAN: See it!
- (GROANS)
ANTAAN: Do you see
what it did to them, John?
- Do you see it?
- (SCREAMS)
ANTAAN: See it!
♪ (MUSIC RISES) ♪
- (DEVICE TURNS OFF)
- ♪ (MUSIC FALLS) ♪
(PANTS)
♪ (PENSIVE MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
(GRUNTS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
♪ (MUSIC CONCLUDES) ♪
The effects
of our collective loss
will remain with you
for some time.
I'm sorry.
The scale of our tragedy
drew the attention
of a Green Lantern
sent by the Guardians.
The Lantern
took the monster
into his custody
and guaranteed
he'd be executed.
- Why?
- ANTAAN: I do not know.
It does not matter,
but we believed, somewhere,
the Manhunter was still alive.
So, we searched, John.
We searched for years.
Until finally we discovered
where he was hiding.
Rushville.
ANTAAN:
Our detection is limited.
There's radiation unique
to the Manhunter,
though he could be disguised
as any human.
To find out which,
we had to get close.
But our team was exposed
and killed.
And who should arrive
an hour later?
Jordan.
You think he was trying
to protect the thing?
ANTAAN: Perhaps.
Our target knows
we've located him.
And we cannot enter Rushville
without being detected.
♪ (LOW TENSE MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
So, you...
you must identify the Manhunter.
How the fuck
am I supposed to do that?
Your bird.
This bird is proof
you can achieve the impossible.
Now, we could fulfill
our mission
by walking into the town square
and detonating ourselves,
but that would destroy
Rushville.
No reason for innocent lives
to be lost.
Because it took a human form,
it could be killed as a human.
You have 48 hours, John.
Find the Manhunter.
Once you do...
contact us.
- If you fail to contact us--
- Yeah, I got it.
♪ (MUSIC FADES) ♪
- (INHALES SHARPLY)
- (MONITOR BEEPING)
KERRY: Hey, there.
They shot me.
KERRY: You were trespassing.
Might as well have walked
onto that ranch
with a sign
that said, "Shoot me."
- How are you feeling?
- Uh, all right.
A little sore.
How long have I been out?
Not too long.
They cleared you to go.
Just wanted you
to sleep off the anesthesia.
(PANTS)
So...
what's with Sinestro?
Why are you asking me that?
KERRY: You kept saying his name
in your sleep.
I'm not authorized
to talk about that.
It's not exactly top secret.
It says here, "He was a Lantern,
attempted a coup,
killed one of the bosses."
It also says you were the one
who took him down.
I don't talk about that.
Except that you do,
in your sleep.
- How...
- (HANDCUFF RATTLES)
You gotta be kidding me.
Like I said,
you were trespassing.
HAL: In the name of Tom Osborne,
or whoever it is
that you worship,
please take these off.
Not until you listen to me.
Can you manage that?
- Yes, ma'am.
- Good.
Because every time
you don't listen,
or you steal bodies,
or storm
my father-in-law's compound
and don't let me do the talking,
what you're really doing
is cutting my legs
straight out from under me.
I'm the sheriff.
If you don't follow my lead,
you're legitimizing this idea
that Macon is the seat of power.
And trust me,
you do not want to help
push that narrative.
This is my town.
I have worked my ass off
to earn people's respect,
and I can't have you
undermining that.
You're right.
I'm sorry. You're right.
So, you're gonna go back
to your motel
and let me do my job?
No more storming the compound?
I swear on Tom Osborne's life.
(HANDCUFF UNLOCKS)
And for the record,
I'm not on your side.
I'm not on Macon's side.
I'm on my side,
trying to hold
this town together.
(SIGHS)
Can I ask you a question?
If I knew
about the alien detectors,
why did I fight you
on jurisdiction?
Does make a guy wonder.
The others were dead.
I assumed if Waylon
didn't set off the alarm,
he wasn't an alien.
I was wrong.
It happens.
KERRY: It shouldn't. Look.
I apologize
for trying to obstruct you.
I just didn't want Billy's dad
insurrecting the shit
out of everyone
and getting them all paranoid
about invasion.
So much for that plan.
Thanks for being straight
with me.
Thanks for not dying
in my jurisdiction.
(CHUCKLES DRYLY)
KERRY: My turn for a question.
Why am I still in town
if the threat's over?
It does make a girl wonder.
Something is off here.
I can feel it.
Why do you want me gone?
Everything feels
like it's about to explode
for no good reason.
This place is losing its mind.
You kicking up dust
and getting shot isn't helping.
If I need you, I can call.
You were at my bedside.
It's a great book.
It's hard to find time
to read with a kid at home.
- (TELEPHONE RINGING)
- ♪ (BROODING MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
(SIGHS) So,
where are you from, anyway?
You decide
to actually make nice,
and that's the best you got?
"Where you from?"
Well, you don't exactly
scream Rushville.
- (SCOFFS) You're a snob.
- Doesn't mean I'm wrong.
I'm from Gotham.
Moved here on a whim.
- That sounds like a story.
- Doesn't it?
- That's all I'm gonna get?
- Pretty much.
Hmm. I'll take it for now.
KERRY:
Because you're not leaving.
You didn't hear a word I said
in there, did you?
Well, I heard a few of 'em.
Where are all the patients?
It's a small town,
not exactly a big patient pool.
♪ (MUSIC BUILDS) ♪
(SIGHS)
Half the equipment looks
like it was just taken out
of the crate.
Yeah, well,
mostly everyone's smart enough
not to get themselves shot.
- (THUNDER RUMBLES)
- ♪ (BROODING MUSIC CONTINUES) ♪
JOHN: Thank you.
Just over here is great.
There you go. Thank you.
- (BELL RINGING)
- (BIRD CHIRPS)
♪ (SOFT COUNTRY MUSIC PLAYING
OVER SPEAKERS) ♪
(FAINT CHATTER)
(DOOR CLOSES)
- (DOOR OPENS)
- (BELL RINGING)
(GROANS) Hey.
- Um, can I get a...
- (DOOR CLOSES)
I... I'll get a decaf, please.
Thank you.
- SERVER: Of course.
- (BIRD TWEETS)
(COOKWARE CLANKING)
- (JOHN SIGHS)
- (DOOR HINGES CREAKING)
It's a small town,
bound to happen.
Yeah.
ZOE MACON: The booths
are more comfortable.
Uh, it's been a long day.
I'm just trying to clear my head
for a second.
Yeah, yeah. Fair enough.
- (COFFEE POURING)
- (THUNDER RUMBLING)
Thank you very much.
- Here you go.
- JOHN: Thanks.
(BIRD TWEETING)
(SIGHS)
Um, for the record,
I wouldn't have slept with you
if I knew you were married.
Well, I'm glad you didn't know.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
You into that kind of thing?
ZOE: What kind of thing is that?
I mean, uh...
is your relationship
unconventional?
You've met my husband, right?
- JOHN: Mm-hmm.
- Mm-hmm.
Yeah. What do you think?
Uh, respectfully? I think
he's pretty fucking weird.
(LAUGHS) Yeah, that he is.
Deeply so.
Yeah. I think
he's pretty fucking weird,
but you're not.
(CUP CLINKS)
- How can you be so sure?
- Uh, I see you. Um...
I don't think
you would do anything
without thinking about it first.
You know?
White men have the privilege
of being eccentric.
White men with money?
They can do
whatever the fuck they want.
Play cowboy, build castles.
- Do you like that?
- ZOE: Yeah. I like the security.
I also like
that he could've bought
some blonde bimbo from Texas
to be his arm candy,
but he wanted me.
I'm sure a lot
of people want you.
ZOE: None...
that could give me what he has.
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
It's a lot to deal with,
I know, but...
but it's worth it, I think.
And when I need a break,
I just take one.
So, you'll put up with some
deeply weird White man
with a savior complex
just to live the life?
No, I'm with my husband
because I love him.
And I know he loves me.
Hey, how's your White man?
(CHUCKLES)
Uh, how is he?
He wanted me out the way,
so he, uh... he sent me
to fetch his things.
Is that why you were trying
to clear your head over there?
Uh...
I'm just trying to figure out
if I can trust him.
ZOE: If you have to ask
the question,
then you already know
the answer.
(CAR ENGINE RUMBLING)
(BIRD CHIRPING)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
JOHN: Nope.
Don't.
What happened to you?
Your girlfriend's husband
sicced one of you sniper-types
on me.
- Oh. Shoulder?
- HAL: Mm-hmm.
Through and through?
Yeah, it's a nice warning shot.
Good to know
you're a fan of his work.
- Yeah.
- (HAL GRUNTS)
- (DISTANT TRAIN HORN BLARING)
- (ZIPPER OPENS)
I told you
not to bring the suit.
Yeah, well,
maybe I couldn't bring myself
to just disrespect it.
What else were you doing
while you were rummaging
through my stuff?
Dance around in my bathrobes?
Sing into my hairbrush?
(LANTERN WHIRRING)
HAL: "In brightest day,
in blackest night,
no evil shall escape my sight.
Let those who worship
evil's might
beware my power,
Green Lantern's light."
- (WHIRRING STOPS)
- (SIGHS)
There's something
on that compound.
Benefactor's the key.
We're not leaving here
until we find out who he is
and what they're hiding.
Yeah.
- Whatever you say.
- (BIRD CHIRPING)
HAL: Hey, you might want to, uh,
check the fine print
on that insurance policy.
What the hell's
all over the seats?
I believe, uh, technically
they call that alien goo.
(CAR DOOR CLOSES)
(CAR DOOR SLAMS SHUT)
(CHUCKLES)
♪ (LOW TENSE MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
What do you know
about Manhunters?
Where'd you hear that word?
Our buddy Waylon had friends.
They followed me onto the plane,
snatched me outside
of your house.
They're convinced
there's a Manhunter
here in Rushville.
(HAL GRUNTS)
So, what did they want with you?
They want me to ID him.
And give him a call in 48 hours.
Otherwise, they'll blow up
half of western Nebraska.
Why you?
Because they don't trust you.
In fact, he made it explicit
that I shouldn't tell you
any of this.
- What else?
- JOHN: Just that he thinks
the Guardians
may have hid the Manhunter here.
- They wouldn't do that.
- Well, shit. That's what I said.
I knew there was something
about this place.
And my gut is never wrong.
(BIRD CHIRPING)
Abin Sur must have brought
him here
and the Manhunter killed him.
Yeah, and then you got
your ring.
What else can you tell me
about Manhunters?
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
It's above
your pay grade, Junior.
JOHN: No, it's not.
I told you he was here.
Oh, so now Mr. Chain of Command
wants me to break the rules?
Hal, they don't know
what form he's taken.
He could be anyone in town.
♪ (MUSIC INTENSIFIES) ♪
What else did they say to you?
You know, just that, um,
to create a living thing,
let alone keeping it alive
while not wearing the ring,
is so advanced
that it's practically
impossible.
But I figured
that couldn't be true,
'cause if it was,
you would've at least given me
a hoorah.
Hoorah.
Forty-eight hours, huh?
Yeah, 48.
You tell the Guardians
any of this?
(BIRD CHIRPING)
JOHN: I report to you.
- Hey.
- What?
HAL:
What's with that bird, anyway?
♪ (MUSIC CONCLUDES) ♪
- What are you talking about?
- The bird.
I mean, you brought it to life
with your subconscious.
It must mean
something pretty deep.
It's just a bird.
(CHIRPS)
(CONSTRUCT WARBLES)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(DOOR OPENS, CLOSES)
♪ (FAST-TEMPO
SYNTH MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
(LANTERN CLANGS)
♪ (DRAMATIC
SYNTH MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
♪ (MUSIC BUILDS) ♪
(CLANGING HUM)
(DOOR HUMS)
- Authorize Hal Jordan.
- ♪ (MUSIC CONCLUDES) ♪
AUTOMATED VOICE: Access granted.
(CELL DOOR WHIRRING)
Sinestro.
Hal.
Tell me what you know
about Manhunters.
♪ ("HUMAN CONDITION"
BY PRETTY SICK PLAYING) ♪
No hello?
No how have I been?
HAL: Hello, Sinestro,
how have you been?
Now, what the fuck do you know
about Manhunters?
If one still existed,
it'd be the second
greatest threat
you're currently facing.
So why don't you tell me
about John Stewart?
♪ ("HUMAN CONDITION"
CONTINUES PLAYING) ♪
♪ She takes my hand
And she pours me a glass ♪
♪ Addiction's a disease
So, I get a pass ♪
♪ I wanna feel something again ♪
♪ She takes my hand
And she asks me to dance ♪
♪ Nothing really matters
If you don't have romance ♪
♪ I wanna feel something again ♪
♪ He takes me out and says
"Let's do business" ♪
♪ He's a bad guy
But I believe in forgiveness ♪
♪ I wanna do something
That matters ♪
♪ Takes a meeting
'Cause he likes my vision ♪
♪ I'm not opportunistic
No, I'm just ambitious ♪
♪ I wanna be someone
That matters ♪
♪ The freedom you're being sold
Is just submission ♪
♪ They wanna keep you content
And under supervision ♪
♪ They got you convinced
That ignorance is bliss in ♪
♪ Some ever changing mind
Erasing human condition ♪
♪ I don't have time
To worry about ♪
♪ If I am stuck
And if there's any way out ♪
♪ I don't have time ♪
♪ (SONG CONCLUDES) ♪